Rahulpreet Singh Bal
Edmonton, AB
(825) 461-3888
rahulpre@ualberta.ca
LinkedIn
GitHub
Portfolio Website

# **Professional Summary**

Motivated university student with 3+ years' experience in programming and solving problems. Strong conceptual and technical knowledge of machine learning techniques and frameworks demonstrated through personal projects. A creative thinker, possessing a drive to use my knowledge and skills to real world problems and provide meaningful solutions and turn ideas into reality. A team player committed to delivering results in a respectful, inclusive, and service-minded manner.

### Skills

- Programming: Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SQL
- Frameworks/Libraries/Tools: Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn ,Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, React,js, Jquery, Node.js, Github
- Version Control: Git
- **Soft Skills:** Leadership, Accountability, Strong attention to detail, Excellent Communication, Patience, Organization, Creativity, Understanding of software lifecycles, Agile Methodology
- Other: MS Office 10 (Excel, Outlook, PowerPoint, and Word), Power-BI, Tableau
- Languages: English, Punjabi, Hindi

### Education

#### **Bachelor of Science**

University of Alberta

Expected Graduation: June 2024

Current GPA: 3.5/4.0 Relevant Courses:

- CMPUT 261 Introduction to AI
- CMPUT 267 Basics of Machine Learning
- CMPUT 291 File and Database Management
- CMPUT 301 Introduction to Software Engineering
- CMPUT 365 Introduction to Reinforcement Learning
- CMPUT 366 Search and Planning in Al

# **Projects**

- 1. Student Headcount prediction [Source]
  - Created a data science regression project which predicts the number of students in the library at a given date and time, created using actual data borrowed from University of Alberta Cameron Library
  - Used Pandas, Numpy and OpenCv for data-cleaning.
  - Matplotlib and seaborn for visualization , Sklearn for training various models and then evaluated them by MSE.
  - Used openGridCV for fine tuning hyperparameters.
- 2. Codekamon [Source]

- A mobile application featuring QR Code scanning for point-earning, with a local QR Code map, leader board and player search feature.
- Used Java and Android Studio for app development, Firebase for the database, Git and GitHub for version control and Agile development technique.

### 3. Image Classification Project [Source]

- Created a data science Classification project which when given an image tells us who
  it is.
- Used Python, Numpy and OpenCv for data-cleaning.
- Matplotlib and seaborn for visualization, Sklearn for model building.
- Python flask for http server .Html,css and javascript for user interface.

## **Achievements and Certifications**

- Dean's Honor Roll 2022-2023
- Intro to Machine Learning Kaggle [Credential]
- Pandas Kaggle [<u>Credential</u>]
- Data Visualization Kaggle [Credential]
- Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning Coursera [Credential]
- Sample-based Learning methods Coursera [Credential]
- Certification in International Learning University of Alberta[2024 Expected]

## **Work Experience**

#### **Event staff**

University of Alberta

Sept 2022 -Present

- Handled organization and smooth running of various sport events like hockey, volley ball, basketball etc.
- Dealt with 2000+ numbers at most events.
- Filled in various roles like ticket authorizing, float counting, stock handling.

#### **Administrative Assistant**

Creative Kitchen Cabinets Inc.

May 2021 - April 2022

- Provided exceptional quality, positive, and friendly experiences to all customers with consistent accuracy.
- Organized and maintained electronic and paper files, ensuring that documents are up-to-date.
- Answered and directed phone calls, responded to emails in a professional manner.

# **Volunteer Experience**

International Student's Association, University of Alberta

 Active member of the group where every year we hold various events to promote our diverse culture and make sure every International student feels like home.

#### **Hundred Rupee Group**

• Founded this group with a group of friends and now has almost 300 members. Every month everyone donated whatever they can afford and at the end of the month the total pooled amount is used to help the ones in dire need.